<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Keith Alpichi</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Keith Alpichi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Success Manifest — Episode 0</title>
      <link>/success-manifest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/success-manifest/</guid>
      <description>What is a Success Manifest What is success really? What qualities make a successful person? What words contribute to this success? Persistence? Focus? Luck?
I created Success Manifest to document my experiences and advice on success from taking a single word and explaining how it relates to success. Following this article and many others, I will devote an entire episode focused on one word.
Here are some of its key components: - it’s focused- each article is focused on a single word rather than success in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is an Express Middleware and How to Create One</title>
      <link>/what-is-express-middleware-and-how-to-create-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what-is-express-middleware-and-how-to-create-one/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  Basic understanding of the HTTP protocol, Javascript, Node, and Express  What are Middlewares? From the documentation,
 Middlewares are functions that have access to the request object (req), the response object (res), and the next function in the application’s request-response cycle. The next function is a function in the Express router which, when invoked, executes the middleware succeeding the current middleware.
 To give you a relatable picture, Express middleware&amp;rsquo;s are the workers in a manufacturing line where each individual has a specific and unique responsibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to setup SASS or LESS with Webpack 2</title>
      <link>/how-to-setup-sass-less-with-webpack-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-to-setup-sass-less-with-webpack-2/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  Basic understanding of SASS or LESS and Webpack  LESS time, more SASS That&amp;rsquo;s what you want in your development workflow. Spend less time configuring and setting up and more time showing off your bad-ass styled applications. Here&amp;rsquo;s a straight-forward explanation to configuring a preprocessor like SASS or LESS with Webpack.
 I haven&amp;rsquo;t tested it yet but the new version of Webpack (3) should still work with this setup</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I went from a Stack Overflow reputation of 100 to 550 in under two months</title>
      <link>/how-to-build-stackoverflow-reputation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-to-build-stackoverflow-reputation/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t Underestimate Stack overflow First off, this achievement may not be a ground-breaking feat but I was happy my approach to answering questions was increasing my reputation at a pretty fast rate. I&amp;rsquo;ve read articles how some people hacked their way to higher reputation but I am going to show you how I did it&amp;hellip; by giving a genuine helpful response as fast as I could after a question was posted.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>